Guide to the Kulchur Foundation records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Kulchur Magazine and Kulchur Press, 1953-1989
  - Subseries II.2: Editorial Files, 1967-1989
    - Kostelanetz, Richard
      - I Articulations, 1974
        - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 3)
        - Proofs, (3 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 4 to 6)
        - Publicity Materials (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Lavin, Stuart R.
      - Let Myself Shine, 1979
        - Manuscript, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 8 to 9)
        - Publicity Material (Box 26, Folder 10)
        - Page Proofs (Box 56)
    - MacAdams, Lewis
      - Live at the Church, 1977
        - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 11)
        - Proofs (Box 26, Folder 12)
        - Promotional Material (Box 26, Folder 13)
        - Cover Art (Box 56)
        - Proofs (Box 56)
    - Malanga, Gerard and Andy Warhol
      - Screen Tests/A Diary, 1966
        - Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 1)
        - Photographs (Box 27, Folder 2)
        - Proofs (Box 27, Folder 3)
        - Release Forms and Permissions (Box 27, Folder 4)
        - Reviews (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Mayer, Bernadette
      - Poetry, 1976
        - Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 6)
        - Paste-up Copy (Box 27, Folder 7)
        - Proofs, (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 8 to 9)
    - North, Charles
      - Leap Year, 1978
        - Manuscript (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Proofs (Box 28, Folder 2)
        - Paste-up Copy (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Notley, Alica
      - Waltzing Matilda, 1981
        - Manuscript (Box 28, Folder 4)
        - Galleys (Box 28, Folder 5)
        - Proofs, (4 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 1 to 4)
        - Paste-up Copy (Box 29, Folder 5)
        - Promotional Material (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Owen, Maureen
      - Hearts in Space, 1980
        - Manuscript (Box 30, Folder 1)
        - Proofs, (5 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 2 to 6)
        - Mechanicals (Box 30, Folder 7)
        - Promotional Material (Box 30, Folder 8)
        - Cover Design and Artwork (Box 58)
    - Owens, Rochelle
      - How Much Paint Does the Paintings Need, 1988
        - Manuscript (Box 31, Folder 1)
        - Proofs (3 Folder) (Box 31, Folder 2 to 4)
      - I am the Babe of Joseph Stalin's Daughter, 1972
        - Manuscript (Box 31, Folder 5)
        - Paste-up Copy (Box 31, Folder 6)
        - Promotional Materials (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Perrault, John
      - Luck, 1969
        - Manuscript (Box 32, Folder 1)
        - Galley proofs (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Plymell, Charles
      - The Trashing of America, 1975
        - Artwork (Box 32, Folder 2)
        - Manuscript, (2 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 3 to 4)
        - Proofs (blueline) (Box 32, Folder 5)
        - Paste-up Copy (Box 32, Folder 6)
        - Reviews (Box 32, Folder 7)
        - Galley Proofs (Box 56)
    - Ratcliff, Carter
      - Fever Coast, 1973
        - Cover Design (Box 32, Folder 8)
        - Manuscript (Box 32, Folder 9)
        - Proofs (Box 32, Folder 10)
        - Promotional Materials (Box 32, Folder 11)
        - Galley Proofs (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Pommy Vega, Janine
      - The Bard Owl, 1980
        - Manuscript (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - Proofs, (3 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 2 to 4)
    - Saroyan, Aram
      - Untitled, 1968
        - Manuscript (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Torregian, Sotère
      - The Age of Gold, 1976
        - Manuscript (Box 33, Folder 6)
        - Proofs (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Towle, Tony
      - New and Selected Poems, 1983
        - Manuscript (Box 34, Folder 1)
        - Proofs, (3 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 2 to 4)
        - Promotional Material (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Violi, Paul
      - In Baltic Circles, 1973
        - Cover Art (Box 34, Folder 6)
        - Manuscript (Box 34, Folder 7)
        - Promotional Material (Box 34, Folder 8)
        - Galley Proofs (Box 59, Folder 6)
        - Cover Design (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Waldman, Anne
      - No Hassles, 1971
        - Manuscript (Box 35, Folder 1)
        - Paste-up Copy (Box 35, Folder 2)
        - Promotional Materials (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Waldman, Anne and Susan Howe
      - Invention, 1985
        - Proofs, (4 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 4 to 7)
    - Warsh, Lewis
      - Blue Heaven, 1978
        - Manuscript (Box 36, Folder 1)
        - Proofs, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 2 to 3)
        - Promotional Materials (Box 36, Folder 4)
        - Galley Proofs (Box 56)
  - Subseries II.3: Unpublished Manuscripts, 1953-1992
    This series includes manuscripts that were submitted to Kulchur, but never published, as well as a small body of work that was submitted to Cover, a little magazine edited and published by Lita Hornick's friend Jeffrey Cyphers Wright.
    - Adam, Helem-- Poems (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Austé-- Poems and Tales, 1976-1979 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Berrigan, Ted-- Review of Joe Ceravolo's Millennium Dust, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Eshleman, Clayton-- "Bouquet," 1965 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      (review of Cid Corman's In Good Time. Submitted to Kulchur but not published.
    - Goodman, Paul-- "Casper's Birthday," 1953 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Ginsberg, Allen-- Note (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Giorno, John-- Cancer of My Ball Manuscript (Box 37, Folder 7)
      (photocopy)
    - Gustafson, Jim-- "Shameless in New York" (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Hamilton, Steve-- Poems (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Higgins, Dick-- Essays, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Jones, LeRoi-- "An Anthology of Chance Observations," 1964 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      (book review)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln-- "Eisenstein," 1963, (2 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Kaplan, Allan, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Katz, Alex-- Drawing (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - MacLow, Jackson-- Poems, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Malanga, Gerard-- Poems, 1964-1990, (3 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 17 to 19)
    - Margolies, Richard (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Monk, Meredith Jane-- "Chacon Trio," 1977 (Box 37, Folder 21)
      (music score inscribed to Lita and Morton Hornick)
    - Olsen, Charles-- "Psychic Subdivisions," 1964 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Owens, Rochelle-- "Chucky's Hunch" and "Gram Atom Lita Poem: Poem for Lita Hornick," 1980-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 23 to 24)
    - Powers, Shirley-- Poems, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - Randall, Margaret (Box 37, Folder 26)
    - Ross, David-- Review (Box 37, Folder 27)
    - Rothenberg, Jerome-- "Words," 1964 (Box 37, Folder 28)
    - Sinclair, John-- Review of A.B. Spellman's The beautiful Days (Box 37, Folder 29)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert-- Review (Box 37, Folder 30)
    - Spellman, A.B.-- Review (Box 37, Folder 31)
    - Torregian, Sotère-- Poems, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 32)
    - Towle, Rachel-- Poems, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 33)
    - Vega, Janine Pommey-- Poems (Box 37, Folder 34)
    - Waldman, Anne-- Poems (Box 37, Folder 35)
    - Weigel, Tom-- "Corker" and "Foot on Pedal" (Box 37, Folder 36)
    - Unidentified, Unpublished Manuscripts (Box 37, Folder 37)
    - Material Submitted to Cover Magazine
      - Brodsky, Louis-- Poems (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Economou, George-- Poems (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Ginsburg, Allen-- "Images From Mind and Space New York City" (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Hughes, Sophie-- Poems (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - McClure, Michael-- Poems (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Nasdor, Marc-- "Returning Vultures" (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Notley, Alice-- "Rubies," 1992 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Oliver, Douglas-- The Lake of the Presidents, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Owens, Rochelle-- Poems (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Padgett, Ron-- Poems (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Pettet, Simon-- "Meulana" (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Rosenthal, Bob-- Poems (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - Trausse, John-- Poems (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - Vega, Janine Pommey-- Poems (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - Viola, Paul-- Poems (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - Warsh, Lewis-- Poems (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Subseries II.4: Administrative and Financial Records, 1961-1994
    Administrative and Financial Records, 1961-1994: This series includes Kulchur's Business and Administrative Files, including files for events sponsored or produced by the Kulchur Foundation as well as financial records, subscription records, and copyright agreements.
    - Advertising, 1964-1965 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Association of Literary Magazines of America (ALMA), 1962-1965 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Authors' Contracts, 1961-1985, (4 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 19 to 23)
    - Copyright and Permissions, 1961-1979 (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - Corporate Documents, 1961-1970 (Box 38, Folder 24)
      (Trademark registration, Board of Directors documents, etc.)
    - Legal Documents (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - Library of Congress Cataloging Documents, 1966-1974 (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - Mailing Lists (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Orders, (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Postage and Mailings (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Permissions, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Marc Schleifer, 1961-1962 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - The Toilet (Box 39, Folder 7)
      (re. Kulchur Foundation co-producing LeRoi Jones's play The Toilet)
    - Publicity
      - Book Announcements (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Book Distribution Lists, (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Book Inventory, (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Invitations, (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Readings and Events
      - Chinese- American Poetry Readings, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - Institute of Contemporary Art Poetry (Philadelphia) Series, 1975-1976, (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 9 to 10)
      - Museum of Modern Art Poetry Readings, 1973-1983, (11 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 11 to 21)
      - Museum of Modern Art Poetry Readings, 1984-1994, (6 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 1 to 6)
        - Video of Poetry 9 at MOMA (betamax) (Box 53)
      - Poetry Evening at the Whitney Museum of American Art, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Poetry Project
        - Program Information (Box 41, Folder 8)
        - Correspondence (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - St. Marks Theater Poetry Reading (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - Newspaper Clippings and Ephemera (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Financial Records
      - Checks, Registers, and Deposit Statements, 1962-1973 (Box 42)
      - Bright Greek Light Company, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 1)
        (re. Kulchur Founadtion co-producing Lionel Abel's play "The Wives")
      - Citadel Press, 1966-1967 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Eastern New Distributirs, 1962-1965 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Evergreen Review Ads, 1964-1986 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Financial Reports, 1961-1962, 1964-1968 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Galerie der Spiegel, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 6)
        (Correspondence and Contracts regarding German Publication of Screen Tests
      - H. Gantt, 1961-1970 (Box 43, Folder 7)
        (correspondence and invoices related to the printing of Kulchur Magazine and Books)
      - Kulchur Advertising Rates (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - Mandarin Books, LTD, 1964-1965 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - National Association of College Stores (NACS), 1963-1964 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - Sanavio, Piero, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - Scorpion Press, 1962-1964 (Box 43, Folder 12)
      - Tax Records, 1968-1973 (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - Subscription Files (Box 44)
- Series III: Lita Hornick Files, 1948-1994
  This series includes Lita Hornick's writings that were unpublished or published by an entity other than Kulchur Press. It includes a number of poems and short essays, many written in collaboration with friends (often written as an exquisite corpse exercise), as well as manuscripts for her full length books, Kulchur Queen and the The Green Fuse. The series also includes manuscripts and research notes related to her Master's Essay and her PhD Dissertation, both from degrees she received at Columbia. The research files for her dissertation include correspondence with friends and associates of Dylan Thomas's with whom she corresponded while researching her dissertation on Thomas.
  - Biographical Materials, (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Lita Hornick Exhibit at Columbia, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    (captions, photos and press release)
  - Poster for University of Pennsylvania's Graduate School of Fine Arts' Exhibit of Kulchur Books/Material, 1983 (Box 57)
  - Writings -- by Hornick
    - "Autobiography" (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - "Alice and Doug" (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - "All Things are Interrelated " (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - "And God Save Al the Route" (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - "Andy Warhol: A Retrospective"-- Introduction (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - "Around New York" (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - "Around the Town" (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - "The Artifice of Eternity" (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - "Auguries of Innocence" (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - "August, 1989" (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - "Baby Boy," 1994 May 23 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - "Beauty is Truth" (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - "Cataract" (Box 45, Folder 16)
      (with Allen Ginsberg and Peter Orlovsky)
    - "Biography I" (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - "Chanel Real Class" (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - "Chaucer's Middle English" (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - "Cheerful Philosophy" (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - "Christ the Tiger" (Box 45, Folder 21)
      (with Bob Rosenthal and Rochelle Kraut)
    - Collaborations, (16 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 22 to 38)
      (with Alice Notley, Doug Oliver, Bernard Heidsieck, Cary Smith, George Economou, Hettie Jones, John Giorno, Kenneth A. Lohf, Marc Nasdor, Micki and Howard Wesson, Paul Violi, Rochelle Owens, Ron Padgett, and Stephen Westfall, as well as unidentified collaborators)
    - "The Cosmos" (Box 45, Folder 39)
      (with Ed Friedman)
    - "Credo" (Box 45, Folder 40)
    - "The Dangerous World" (Box 45, Folder 41)
    - "Dark and Light" (Box 45, Folder 42)
    - "David Antin, Debunker of the Real" (Box 45, Folder 43)
    - "Death and Renewal" (Box 45, Folder 44)
    - "Deep and Dark Blue" (Box 45, Folder 45)
      (with Paul Violi)
    - "A Desire for Order" (Box 45, Folder 46)
      (with Lewis Warsh)
    - "Doom is Dark" (Box 45, Folder 47)
    - "Dream" (Box 45, Folder 48)
    - "Dream Land" (Box 45, Folder 49)
    - "Dream Time and Waking" (Box 45, Folder 50)
    - "Evil" (Box 45, Folder 51)
    - "Faith" (Box 45, Folder 52)
    - "Fall in the Night" (Box 45, Folder 53)
    - "Fashion's Parties and Nightmares" (Box 45, Folder 54)
    - Free Association, (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 55)
    - "Great Expectations/Poor realizations" (Box 45, Folder 56)
    - "Guilt" (Box 45, Folder 57)
    - "Harmony and Nature" (Box 45, Folder 58)
    - "Historical Observations" (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - "Homage to Alexander Pope" (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - "Homage to Alexander Pope II" (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - "Homage to Allen Ginsberg II" (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - "Homage to Andrew Marvell" (Box 46, Folder 5)
      (with Alice Notley and Doug Oliver)
    - "Homage to Andrew Marvell" (Box 46, Folder 6)
      (with John Giorno)
    - "Homage to Andrew Marvell" (Box 46, Folder 7)
      (with Ron Padgett)
    - "Homage to Dylan Thomas" (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - "Homage to Helen Adam" (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - "Homage to Helen Adam II" (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - "Homage to John Keats" (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - "Homage to John Keats II" (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - "Homage to Ted Berrigan" (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - "Homage to William Blake I" (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - "Homage to William Blake II" (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - "Home" (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - "I Am Happy Now" (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - "I Am So Happy," 1991 (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - "I Believe" (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - "Impressions/Expressions" (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Introduction to "One More Beat" (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - "Italian Schools" (Box 46, Folder 22)
      (with Simon Pettet)
    - "Juliet" (Box 46, Folder 23)
    - "L'Allegro," 1994 (Box 46, Folder 24)
    - "Ladies Who Lunch," 1991 (Box 46, Folder 25)
      (with Anne Waldman)
    - "Let's Call it Autumn," 1992 (Box 46, Folder 26)
      (with Stephen Westfall)
    - "The Little Engine that Could" (Box 46, Folder 27)
      (with Jeff Wright)
    - "Love" (Box 46, Folder 38)
    - "MacBeth" (Box 46, Folder 29)
      (with Marc Nasdor)
    - "Mariana" (Box 46, Folder 30)
    - "Mom," 1992 (Box 46, Folder 31)
      (with Janine Vega)
    - "Moving to Paris," 1992 (Box 46, Folder 32)
      (with Douglas Oliver and Alice Notley)
    - "New City," 1992 (Box 46, Folder 33)
    - "The New York School" (Box 46, Folder 34)
    - "Now Let Me Think," 1992 (Box 46, Folder 35)
    - "Nymphs" (Box 46, Folder 36)
    - "Positive," 1992 (Box 46, Folder 37)
    - "A Quest for Order" (Box 46, Folder 38)
    - "Revelation" (Box 46, Folder 39)
    - "Ripeness is All" (Box 46, Folder 40)
    - "Robin Hood" (Box 46, Folder 41)
    - "Romantic Agony" (Box 46, Folder 42)
    - "Sequel," 1991 (Box 46, Folder 43)
    - "Shall I Compare Thee…" (Box 46, Folder 44)
    - "Sharks at Sea,"1992 (Box 46, Folder 45)
      (with Alice Notley and Douglas Oliver)
    - "The Sky" (Box 46, Folder 46)
    - "Song of Experience" (Box 46, Folder 47)
    - "Sprained Ankle," 1992 (Box 46, Folder 48)
    - "Survive" (Box 46, Folder 49)
    - 'Thoughts of a Collection," 1992 March (Box 46, Folder 50)
    - "Time (Box 46, Folder 51)
    - "To Allen Ginsberg" (Box 46, Folder 52)
    - To Elizabeth and Eleanor-- Manuscript and Publication (Box 46, Folder 53)
    - "Twisted Light," 1992 (Box 46, Folder 54)
    - "The Universe," 1992 (Box 46, Folder 55)
    - "White Mink" (Box 46, Folder 56)
    - "Why I Love Gay Men" (Box 46, Folder 57)
    - "Wine Dark Sea," 1992 (Box 46, Folder 58)
      (with Jeff Wright and Val Oisteanu)
  - Research and Scholarship
    - "Dorothy M. Richardson: The Quest for Selfhood, 1949" (Box 47, Folder 1)
      (Lita Hornick's Masters Essay)
    - "The Intricate Image: A Study of Dylan Thomas"
      (Lita Hornick's Dissertation)
      - Research Correspondence
        - General (Box 47, Folder 2)
        - Bottrall, Ronald, 1955 (Box 47, Folder 3)
        - Campbell, Roy, 1956 (Box 47, Folder 4)
        - Daiches, David, 1955 (Box 47, Folder 5)
        - Eberhart, Richard, 1955 (Box 47, Folder 6)
        - Epson, William, 1955 (Box 47, Folder 7)
        - Johnson, Pamela Hansford (Lady Snow), 1955-1956 (Box 47, Folder 8)
        - Richardson, Dorothy, 1948 (Box 47, Folder 9)
        - Watkins, Vernon, 1955-1956 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Manuscript, (3 Folders) (Box 47, Folder 11 to 13)
      - Manuscript (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Publication (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Publications
    - Kulchur Queen
      - Manuscript
        - Book Manuscript (Box 48, Folder 3)
        - Introduction, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 4)
        - Ashberry Chapter, 1972 (Box 48, Folder 5)
        - Ed Dorn Chapter, 1973 (Box 48, Folder 6)
        - John Giorno Chapter, 1973 (Box 48, Folder 7)
        - Rochelle Owens Chapter, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 8)
        - Anne Waldman Chapter, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 9)
        - Dorothy Richardson Chapter, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 10)
        - Gerard Malanga Chapter, 1974, (2 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 11 to 12)
          (One of the Folders is Hornick's manuscript for the Chapter. The other is research material)
        - Diane Wakoski Chapter, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 13)
        - Kulchur Chapter, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - Page Mock-ups and Captions (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - Proofs, (3 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 16 to 18)
      - Reviews and Announcements (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - The Green Fuse
      - Manuscript, (2 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 20 to 21)
      - Proofs, (2 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 22 to 23)
      - Cover Art (Box 57)
      - Photographs (Box 57)
      - The Herald (newspaper) December 24, 1971- January 8, 1972 five copies (Box 57)
        (includes a review)
  - Research Notes (Box 49-50)
    (on index cards-- primarily research for Night Flight, and Kulchur Queen.)
- Series IV: Photographs, 1950s-1990s
  The photographs series is a relatively small series that includes professionally taken portraits of Lita and her family as well as a number of snapshots and candid photos of Ms. Hornick with her family and friends. Of interest, as well, are snapshots taken at some of the parties thrown by Lita and Morton Hornick. There are also photographs of artworks sent to Ms. Hornick by art galleries so that she, an enthusiastic art collector, could preview new works.
  - Artwork-- Sent from Galleries for Ms. Hornick to Preview, (2 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Balanchine in the Studio (Box 51, Folder 3)
    (for Kulchur 10)
  - Family Photos, (2 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Family Portraits-- Taken by Gerard Malanga (Box 54)
  - Parties (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 51, Folder 7)
- Series V: Artwork, 1965-1980
  This small series includes artwork from the collection of Lita and Morton Hornick, including several pieces by Joe Brainard. Artwork that was acquired as cover art or illustrations for a book published by Kulchur will be found in the editorial files for that publication, rather than as part of this Artwork Series.
  - Brainard, Joe
    - [Fishbowl], 1975 (Box 54)
    - "For Lita," 1965 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      (collage, from collection of Lita and Morton Hornick)
    - "Go, Lovely Rose" (Box 51, Folder 9)
      (pen and ink-- from the collection of Lita and Morton Hornick)
    - "Madonna with flowers VI," 1966 (Box 58)
    - [Teddy Bear], 1960s (Box 51, Folder 10)
      (ink wash-- from the collection of Lita and Morton Hornick)
  - Giordano, Joe-- [Shoes], 1980 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Lamigan-Schmidt, Thomas-- Collages (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Schneeman, George-- Prints (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Serra, Richard-- Sketches (Box 51, Folder 14)
- Series VI: Publications, 1961-1993
  This series is comprised of periodicals, printed books, and broadsides and includes material published by Kulchur Press, material written by Lita Hornick, and books and periodicals in Lita Hornick's Collection.
  - Periodicals
    - General (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Cleopatra I-V, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Cover, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Exquisite Corpse, 1983, 1985 (Box 54)
    - The Floating Bear, 1961-1967 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      (issues 6-27, 29, 31, 34)
    - John O' London's, 1961 May-December (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - MOMA Members Quarterly, 1990 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      (includes an article about the poetry series organized by Lita Hornick and the Kulchur Foundation)
    - The Nation, 1962 May 19 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      (mentions Kulchur on page 434)
    - Newspapers and Clippings, (2 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Poesie Sonore-Poesie Action, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Work / 2, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Printed Broadsides-- Wild Oats Compilation (Box 58)
      (poets include James Schuyler, Kenward Elmslie, Joe Brainard, Ron Padgett, Tom Clark; Brother Antoninus. The Rose of Solitude; Ginsberg, Allen. Kral Majales;McClure, Michael. Two for Bruce Conner)
    - Books
      - Berrigan, Ted-- "Many Happy Returns: To Dick Gallup," 1967 (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence-- "Berlin" and "One Thousand Fearful Words for Fidel Castro" (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - Published by Kulchur (Box 53)
        - Millennium Dust, Joe Ceravolo (Box 53)
        - Sung Sex, Kenward Elmslie and Joe Brainard (Box 53)
        - Night Flight, Lita Hornick (Box 53)
        - Interlocking Lives, Alex Katz and Kenneth Koch (Box 53)
      - Written by Hornick
        - The Green Fuse, Lita Hornick (Box 53)
        - For Elizabeth and Eleanor Great Queens Who Loved Poetry, Lita Hornick (Box 53)
        - Kulchur Queen, Lita Hornick (Box 53)
        - Nine Martinis, Lita Hornick (Box 53)
        - The Intricate Image, Lita Hornick (Box 53)
      - Part of Hornick's Collection
        - License to Carry a Gun, Andrei Codrescu (Box 53)
      - You Bet, Ted Greenwald (Box 53)
      - Common Sense, Ted Greenwald (Box 53)